Zecheng Yin

Shenzhen, China | yinzecheng.cuhk@gmail.com | +86 17728153439 | yonggie.github.io linkedin.com/in/zecheng-yin-95ba8416a | github.com/yonggie

Hard-working bee

I'm a fanatic about cutting-edge researches about Robotics, VLM/LLM, Computer Vision and Graph Data mining. Currently I am a researcher and engineer in Shenzhen Future Network of Intelligence Institute (FNii-Shenzhen) led by fellow of Canadian Academy of Engineering, Shuguang Cui about robotics navigation, arm robot manipulation and VLMs and working closely with Yatong Han and Prof. Zhen Li in The Chinese University of Hong Kong(Shenzhen).

In my M.S., I was advised by Prof. Yanchun Zhang and Hong Yang in the area of Medicine data mining at Guangzhou University. During this period, I had an internship as algorithm engineer at Kuaishou for NLP data mining and an internship as algorithm engineer at IDEA for financial graph malware detection.

Prior to M.S., I was advised by Prof. Jin Li in the area of Federated Learning and Attack at Guangzhou University when in B.S.. I was selected into the AI&Robotics program and exchanged in University of Washington and mentored by Melody Su in 2018.

Publications

Navigation with VLM framework: Go to Any Language, ICRA'25 (Under Review) Zecheng Yin , Shuguang Cui, Zhen Li	Sept 2024
TCMCoRep: Traditional Chinese Medicine Data Mining with Contrastive Graph Representation Learning, KSEM'23 (ccf-c, acceptance rate: 23.1%) <i>Zecheng Yin</i> , Jinyuan Luo, Yanchun Zhang	Sept 2023
HGCL: Heterogeneous Graph Contrastive Learning for Traditional Chinese Medicine Prescription Generation, HIS'22 (acceptance rate: 27.78%) Zecheng Yin, Yanchun Zhang	Sept 2022
A hybrid-scales graph contrastive learning framework for discovering regularities in traditional Chinese medicine formula, BIBM'21 (ccf-b, acceptance rate: 19.6%) Yingpei Wu, Zecheng Yin , Yanchun Zhang	Sept 2021
ResMGCN: Residual Message Graph Convolution Network for Fast Biomedical Interactions Discovering, Arxiv2023 <i>Zecheng Yin</i>	Aug 2022
Education	

Education

CDA 0 4/F 0

• GPA: 3.4/5.0	
Guangzhou University, BS in Computer Science	Sept 2016 – May 2020
• GPA: 3.38/5.0	
University of Washington, AI&robotics program	Aug 2018 – Sept 2018
certificate of excellence	

Experience

Research Engineer, CUHK(Shenzhen)-FNii, Shenzhen

Guangzhou University, M.S. in Computer Science

July 2023 – present

Sept 2020 - May 2023

- Robotics research and implementation in simulators and reality.
- SLAM and navigation and competitions in behavior-1k and habitat3.
- Arm manipulation with LLM generated PDDL.
- RAG-based LLM-powered system.

NLP Algorithm Engineer, Kuaishou, Beijing

May 2021 - June 2022

- Text searching alignment by designed transformers and contrastive learning.
- Construct text dataset and calculate stuffs by long SQL.

Algorithm Engineer Intern, IDEA, Shenzhen

June 2022 – Oct 2022

- 2 transferrable graph embedding (graph sage and random walk) experiments, see github repo1 and repo2
- Implementation of PPRGO.

Projects

SLAM & Navigation in omnigibson and habitat3 simulator

2024

• Free exploration in the scene and simultaneously construct the map using point cloud.

Chinese Poetry Dataset

check the repo

• I volunteered to clean the Chinese poetry raw data and opensourced it as dataset, got 100+ star.

PyG(pytorch geometric) contributer

check the repo

• I implemented simplified graph embedding paper DMGI and contributed the examples to the PyG project and became a project contributor.

Online Federated Learning platform via FATE

2023

• Designed and built a online federated learning service via FATE, along with all back-end services including file operating, storage logic, etc..

Skills

Languages: Python, bash, C++, SQL

Proficiency at: Linux, Pytorch, Flask, ROS, Latex, C++